Inventory of the T. Blake Kennedy Papers, 1892-1957
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center
T. Blake Kennedy papers
1892-1957
Kennedy, T. Blake
00405
4.34 cubic ft. (10 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Collection contains a detailed two-volume memoir written by Kennedy in 1956; correspondence dealing with court cases and other legal matters (1924-1957); speeches and addresses (1950-1956); opinions of cases (1924-1955); and six scrapbooks.
Biography or History
T. Blake Kennedy (1874-1957) served as the U.S. District Court Judge of Wyoming from 1922-1955. Born in Oakland County, Michigan, Kennedy graduated from Franklin College, Franklin, Michigan, in 1895. He began practicing law in Syracuse, New York, with his partner Rodrick M. Matson. In 1901 Matson and Kennedy moved their practice to Cheyenne, Wyoming. One of their first cases was the defense of Tom Horn. Horn was accused of murdering a thirteen year old boy in 1901. Although, Kennedy lost the case, he and the other attorneys received a great deal of notoriety. In addition to his expanding law practice, Kennedy served as Referee in Bankruptcy for the State of Wyoming from 1903-1913. In 1906 he married Anna Lyons. He was temporarily appointed to serve as the federal judge presiding over U.S. District Court of Wyoming in 1921. In 1922, his appointment became permanent, and he held the position until his retirement in 1955. One of his most celebrated cases was the Teapot Dome Lawsuit, (United States vs. Mammoth Oil Company) in 1925. Kennedy also presided over other controversial cases that were reported across the country. He was also occasionally temporarily assigned to Washington DC, Colorado, New Mexico, and Kansas. Judge and Mrs. Kennedy were childless and frequently traveled both within and without the United States. He was active in local, state, and national Republican Party politics. Prior to his judgeship, he held the position of State Chairman for the Republican Party. His other activities included membership in the Masonic Lodge and other civic groups including a literary society and the Frontier Day Heels. In 1951, he received an honorary Ph.D. from the University of Wyoming. Although he retired in November of 1955, he would continue to occasionally fill in for judges or write opinions.
Scope and Content
This collection encompasses T. Blake Kennedy’s life from 1892 until his death, May 1957. It includes his memoirs, personal and professional correspondence, court assignments, speeches and written works on a variety of subjects, and scrapbooks of newspaper articles concerning cases, social engagements, and politics. His views about politics, current events, special cases he represented as an attorney and or presided over within the judicial system, as well as his personal/social and political life are included within his memoirs. Individuals mentioned include local and national political leaders, leading Wyoming citizens, and other judges and attorneys and clients. Cases included Tom Horn, Teapot Dome, Heart Mountain WWII induction resisters. Papers and addresses include speeches made to his various civic, political, and professional organizations, eulogies, and written works concerning issues of the day. His scrapbooks consist of newspaper articles regarding his everyday as well as his most celebrated cases. Other cases of special interest include Mormon polygamy as Mann Act Violations, prostitution and prohibition (Volstead Act), crimes and issues on the Wind River Indian Reservation and other federal lands, constitutional rights issues, and juvenile legal issues.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Blake at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
The T. Blake Kennedy papers were received from the estate of T.Blake Kennedy in accordance with an October 1949 agreement with the University Archives and Western Manuscripts Collection, University of Wyoming. The collection arrived in generally good condition in the latter part of 1957. After several decades of use, it has been reprocessed for preservation reasons. A research copy was made of the original memoir. Volume binders were removed and folder titles were developed. Each series title and most folder titles are T. Blake Kennedy’s. Generally the original order, which is chronological and by form with a few exceptions, was maintained. Exceptions are in Series II, where due to the amount or interest in the subject correspondence, separate folders were developed.
Access Terms
World War, 1939-1945.; Japanese Americans -- Evacuation and Relocation.; Law -- United States; Law -- Wyoming; Oil Fields -- Wyoming; Wyoming -- History -- 1890-1918; Wyoming -- History -- 1919-1945; Wyoming -- History -- 1946-; Scrapbooks; Memoirs
Politics, Government, and Law; Civil Procedure and Courts; Laws and Legislation; Wyoming
Container List
- T. Blake Kennedy - Memoirs, 1956-1957; Series I.
  - Memoir Chapters, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folders 1-29)
  - Memoir Chapters, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folders 1-8)
- Letters to and from a Judge., 1920-1957; Series II.
  - Teapot Dome Correspondence, 1924-1939 (Box 2, Folders 9-10)
  - General Correspondence, 1932,1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Republican Political Correspondence, 1920, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 1924-1930 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - U.S. Senator Candidate Letters, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence and Cases, 1931-1941 (Box 2, Folders 15-17)
  - Correspondence - Elmer Conolgue Family, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence, Miscellaneous Cases, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, War Cases, Heart Mountain, Polygamy, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - General and Personal Correspondence and Records, 1930-1957 (Box 2, Folders 21-23)
  - Honorary Degree and 30 years of service (photo), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - General Correspondence, Miscellaneous Cases, 1949-1955 (Box 2, Folders 25-26)
  - Correspondence - Retirement, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence – Cases – Loose Ends, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Opinions of T. Blake Kennedy 1923-1954, Series III.
  - Instructions of Dispositions of Opinions, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Assignments, 1923-1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Case numbers and Opinions of T. Blake Kennedy, No date (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Instructions to Juries, No date (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Other District Court of U.S. – Cases and Opinions, No date (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals – 8th and 10th, 1923-1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Papers and Addresses 1892-1957, Series IV.
  - Franklin College, 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Syracuse, New York, 1897-1900 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cheyenne, 1901-1930 (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
  - Cheyenne, 1901-1956 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- Personal Scrapbooks 1892-1957, Series V.
  - Personal Scrapbooks, 1892-1957 (Box 5-9, Folder 6)
  - Original Manuscript of memoir. Very Fragile. Use the copy found in Box 1 and 2, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)